Okay, so in this video then, we are going
to discuss the resource management plan.
Now the resource management plan,
remember, just like any management plan,
it is one of the subsidiary
management plans
that make up the project management plan.
And again, just like any
other management plan,
it is documenting how is
documenting procedures.
In this case, it's documenting procedures
regarding resources.
and procedures regarding both physical
resources as well as team resources.
Now, one of the important things,
though, one of the important differences
here with the resource
management plan is that
it is made up of several
different components.
So let's talk about these different
components.
So first one, identification of resources.
So first of all, if we've identified any
resources, that we would
document them here.
And again, resources meaning both physical
and team resources.
resources, equipment, supplies,
labor, raw materials, machines, right?
As well as obviously, you know, part of
the labor, meaning team members as well.
So if you've identified any, we will
document them here.
If we haven't identified them,
then we're going to be documenting how
we're going to identify the materials and
facilities and whatever
it is that we need.
And also when we're going to identify
them.
So as a simple example, let's say we have,
so let's say it's a two or three year
project and we're looking at an activity
that's not going to start until this time
next year, well, we're not
necessarily going to start
scheduling all of our resources
for that activity right now.
We're going to, you know,
we're going to think about
reschedule those resources
more closer to the time.
And again, depending on the size and
nature of the project, right, might be a
few weeks before or a
few months before, but
certainly not, you know,
a whole year before.
So when are we going to start looking at
scheduling some of the resources,
scheduling team members and scheduling
equipment and raw materials for this
particular activity that won't occur until
this time next year?
So that's going to be documented
here as part of the identification
of resources as part of the
resource management plan.
Also, acquiring resources, what are all
the procedures for actually physically,
you know, finding, you know, finding
resources?
resources, right?
And again, both, this refers to both, team
resources as well as physical resources.
So equipment, supplies, raw materials,
labor, are they in-house?
We need to use these machines,
where is the machines located?
We need people with
these skill sets, well, which
departments are they
going to be coming from?
So how are we going to identify them?
But they could also be external to the
organization.
So there could be the internal,
there could be external.
And so this is now going to overlap with
procurement.
So we're going to be
talking about contracts
and stuff in the procurement
management section.
But again, how are we going to acquire our
resources?
Are they internal to the organization?
External, you're going to have different
procedures based on whether they're
internal to the organization or external
to the organization.
So again, this is one of the components of
the resource management plan.
Again, we're documenting procedures,
in this case procedures for resources.
Some additional components of the resource
management plan,
roles and responsibilities.
Now roles and responsibilities here then
specifically refers to team resources.
So it's going to include things like the
Racy chart, right, which is covered in a
separate video, right,
what responsibilities people
have, what all the different
roles are on the project.
Plus it's going to include include things
like the job description or the role
description for the different roles on the
project, is really documenting authority,
responsibility,
competencies and skill sets
as well for each of the particular roles.
So again, those are all going to be
documented here in the roles and
responsibilities section of the
Resource Management Plan
and roles and responsibilities
for all team members.
So including the project manager as well.
Now, the authority level of a project
manager is primarily, initially,
is going to be documented in the project
charter, but it's also, the detailed roles
and responsibility is going to be
documented here, right, in the roles and
responsibility section of the resource
management plan.
Also, along with that, we have the project
org chart.
Who is reporting to who on your project?
So it's really showing reporting structure
within the actual project itself.
So this is not the organizational chart.
That's not the OBS organizational
breakdown structure.
This is the project org chart.
Who is reporting to who on the actual
project itself?
Also, team resource management.
So now that we have identified,
now that we've identified, say,
team members, once we've
identified team members, then
what are the procedures for
rolling them onto a project?
and what's the procedure for rolling them
off a project.
Whereas, if I go back two slides here,
whereas acquiring resources specifically
refers to, you know, where are we going to
find our team members?
How are we going to find our team members?
Acquiring resources, that's what that is
referring to.
Where are we going to find our team
members?
How are we going to identify team members?
Whereas the project team resource
management is saying, once we have
identified team members, then what is the
procedures for rolling them onto a
project, rolled them off a project,
and so on and so forth?
So we've identified a team member,
well, procedures might be something as
simple as, you know, make
sure they have access to
this file, make sure they
have access to this building.
Before team members can start working on
the project, we have to make sure that
they've read these documents, right,
make sure we get a sign off that they have
read this document or they need to sign
off that they've read this document,
or make sure they have access to,
you know, again, you know, certain files,
certain folders, certain directories,
and so on and so forth.
So that's all, you know, procedures for
rolling staff onto a project.
Right, then same thing, rolling staff off
a project.
Once the work has been
complete, what are the
procedures for rolling them off a project?
Who's going to verify that the work is
complete?
Right.
Then we can roll them off a project.
Remember, team members are coming and
going on your project.
And we're talking about predictive here
generally.
In predictive environment,
team members are coming
and going on your project
as and when required.
You don't have your entire
project team right from the beginning
of the project all the way
until the end of the project.
Team members are coming and going as and
when required.
So, again, what are the procedures?
How do we know that this team member's
work is done?
Who's going to sign off in it?
Then what is the procedures for them
rolling off the project?
make sure we revoke access to a certain
file, for example.
And then also in between as well.
So basically, you know, general
guidance on how the team is
going to be staffed and managed
throughout the project as well.
Then another component is the training.
If there's any specific training
requirements, that's going to be
documented here, again in the resource
management plan.
But what happens if we identify some training
requirements later on in the project?
then what are the procedures for that?
Who's going to sign off on that?
Where are we going to get the funding?
So again, that's all
going to be documented
here as part of the
resource management plan.
Then we have team development as well.
Now, the difference
between team development
and training, because
they sound very similar.
The difference is with
training, training is an individual,
an individual team member
gaining a new skill set.
Whereas team development is more team
interaction and team building.
Team members getting to know one another.
Again, your project is only as good as
your team.
You want your team members to get to know
one another.
You want your team members to work better
together.
Generally, when team
members get to know one
another, they usually
work a lot better together.
So, you know, how are we going to have
team members interacting with one another?
How we're going to create our team
building activities, right?
So that's what team development refers to.
And then resource control, monitoring
controlling.
How are we going to monitor and control?
And this primarily refers to physical
resources, but how are we going to monitor
and control our equipment, supplies,
raw materials, and so and so forth.
And then you have the recognition plan,
which primarily refers to a team,
a team resources.
How are we going to recognize strong
performers?
remember also the number one success
factor on any project is stakeholder
engagement if all of your stakeholders are
engaged and motivated on your project
right then that is generally considered
the number one success factor on your
project now again that's obviously easier
said than done but your team members are
stakeholders on your project so you want
to engage and motivate your team members.
And one of the ways of doing that is
having some kind of recognition plan,
recognizing strong
performers, having a reward,
some kind of rewards
plan or a recognition plan.
So again, they can feel a little
motivated.
That doesn't always work
in reality, but you know, in
theory it should be there
and in theory it would work.
So recognition plan is also a component of
the resource management plan.
Okay.
So these are, the main major components
then of the resource management plan,
make sure that you know what all of these
components are.
Because on the exam, they could refer to
any of these components.
And so, again, any management plan is
documenting procedures.
And in this case, resource
management plan are documenting
procedures for all of these
components that we just discussed.
Okay.